<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ictia Coaching</title>
    <link>https://ictia.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ictia Coaching</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 07:29:50 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ictia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test post</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 07:29:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>A test post from dharmabum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating of Perceived Exertion - RPE</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/rpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:10:02 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/rpe/</guid>
      <description>Ideally you would measure exercise intensity by monitoring your heart rate. However, not everyone has a heart rate monitor readily available. You could measure it by stopping and taking your pulse at regular intervals&amp;hellip;But, there is an alternative that works remarkably well: the Rating of Perceived Exertion, or RPE, also known as the Borg scale.
A Rating of Perceived Exertion is perhaps the most basic way to express the intensity you are experiencing during an exercise, and yet for all its simplicity, it has great value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make exercise a habit and part of a routine</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/habit_routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 11:58:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/habit_routine/</guid>
      <description>A habit is something that a person does often, in a regular and repeated way.
A routine is a specific set of habits done in a particular order.
For instance, a regular morning routine could be: wake up, go to the toilet, brush your teeth, get dressed, eat breakfast, drink coffee, go out the door. The whole is a routine, the individual aspects are habits.
If your days are more or less the same every day, with perhaps some deviation over the weekend, then you have a daily routine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cardio?</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/cardio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:28:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/cardio/</guid>
      <description>Simply put, a cardiovascular exercise or cardio is an exercise that elevates your heart and breathing rates, effectively pumps your heart rate up to 60% - 70% of its maximum, for at least 20 minutes, improving your heart, lungs, and circulatory system.
Types of Cardio      Steady State (SS)
Exercising at a continuous, steady effort.
  High Intensity Interval Training (HIIT)
Switching between short periods of intense exercise and brief periods of recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the bicycle?</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 10:13:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/bicycle/</guid>
      <description>I come from a cycling nation, so the bicycle is always high on my mind.
Compared to running, cycling has far less impact on your joints, namely knees and hips, it feels less strenuous yet is a great vehicle for improving your health.
Cycling relaxes my mind, after a while, and certainly out in the countryside, it wanders off into all kinds of new and interesting directions. A good exercise brings peace of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICTIA</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ictia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 10:33:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ictia/</guid>
      <description>Ictia is an acronym in the spirit of René Descartes.
 I Cycle Therefore I Am
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Finland to the Netherlands by bicycle</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/finland_netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:40:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/finland_netherlands/</guid>
      <description>One could say that I grew up cycling. Some of my earlier memories are of me learning to cycle in Purmerend, 20 kilometers or so to the north of Amsterdam. I remember later on trying to break my speed records while checking my speedometer, which at the time (the early 1970s) was a large handlebar mounted contraption. During my teens I road-raced and I have basically enjoyed cycling my whole life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/services/</guid>
      <description>Level 1 coaching plan     Athlete profile  Absolute beginner   Duration  1 month   What you get  Consultation where we&amp;rsquo;ll evaluate your level of fitness, your goals, and potential scheduling issues Basic training plan (25 - 50 kilometers per week) After 2 weeks evaluation and, if needed, training plan update   Price  €50    Level 2 coaching plan     Athlete profile  You are no longer an absolute beginner and want to take basic endurance building to the next level   Duration  1 month   What you get  Consultation where we&amp;rsquo;ll evaluate your level of fitness and your goals Structured workout plan designed to match your fitness level and tailored to your cycling goals (50 - 100 kilometers per week) Training zones based on MHR or RPE Weekly evaluation and, if needed, training plan update Device file data analysis (if available)   Price  €100    Location based     Basic bike-fit - €25 Basic bike overhaul - fix flat tyres, lube chain, making the bike rideable again - €35 + material   All coaching is private and one-on-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Ictia Coaching is a cycling coaching company that helps people develop themselves to be the best they can be. The main focus is on complete beginners and entry-level cyclists. Athletes receive support through one-on-one coaching, educational blogging and focused structured training plans. The mission is to help unique people achieve their personal goals.
 Helping unique people achieve personal goals
 My story    I have been a cyclist whole my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me:</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Loading… </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
