<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ictia Cycling</title>
    <link>https://ictia.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ictia Cycling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 18:55:42 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ictia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GPS, Navigation Apps, and Sites for Cyclists</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/gps-navapps-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 18:55:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/gps-navapps-sites/</guid>
      <description>Cycling has become an increasingly popular form of transportation and exercise. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned pro or just starting out, navigation apps can be a great tool to help you plan and navigate your routes. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at some of the cycling navigation apps and sites. The focus is the importing of GPX files, for instance routes downloaded from the Lake Trails’ website, and on mobile friendly solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 2 training</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/zone-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 11:56:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/zone-2/</guid>
      <description>Endurance cycling is a sport that requires a high level of cardiovascular fitness and endurance. One of the most effective ways to improve these areas is through zone 2 training.
Zone 2 training, also known as aerobic training, involves working at a moderate intensity level where the body is able to use oxygen to produce energy. This type of training is specific to endurance sports like cycling, where the goal is to maintain a steady pace for long periods of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fartlek</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/fartlek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/fartlek/</guid>
      <description>Fartlek training is a popular and effective method of training for endurance cycling. The name &amp;ldquo;fartlek&amp;rdquo; comes from the Swedish word for &amp;ldquo;speed play,&amp;rdquo; which is an accurate description of this type of training. The idea behind fartlek training is to incorporate bursts of high-intensity effort into a moderate-intensity workout.
One of the main benefits of fartlek training is that it improves cardiovascular fitness. The high-intensity bursts of effort challenge the body to work harder, which in turn increases the size and strength of the heart and lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Intensity Interval Training</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/hiit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 08:28:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/hiit/</guid>
      <description>This is a form of workout where you switch between short periods of intense exercise and brief periods of recovery. Most of the time the intense periods are between 30 seconds and up to 5 minutes. The level of intensity during every interval should in principle be &amp;lsquo;all-out&amp;rsquo;, you will be reaching your VO2Max and anaerobic zone.
Although HIIT is all the craze nowadays it should not be taken lightly, and only considered after you have completed a good base period and your body has properly adapted and is ready for more intensive workouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steady State Training</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 13:05:32 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ss/</guid>
      <description>Steady state training is the opposite of HIIT. It requires maintaining a specific heart rate below the maximum of your targeted zone for an extended period of time. Simply stated, it is a cardio workout that calls for a continuous and steady effort, whereas an HIIT workout requires a varying energy output.
Benefits great for beginners starting out on a workout routine less stress on muscles and joints helps in recovery after harder workouts like HIIT it helps to improve endurance and conditioning without too much stress on the body Pros and Cons As a steady state workout is usually done at a low to moderate intensity, workouts tend to be longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Finland to the Netherlands by bicycle</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/finland_netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 10:40:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/finland_netherlands/</guid>
      <description>One could say that I grew up cycling. Some of my earlier memories are of me learning to cycle in Purmerend, 20 kilometers or so to the north of Amsterdam. I remember later on trying to break my speed records while checking my speedometer, which at the time (the early 1970s) was a large handlebar mounted contraption. During my teens I road-raced and I have basically enjoyed cycling my whole life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make exercise a habit and part of a routine</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/habit_routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 11:58:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/habit_routine/</guid>
      <description>A habit is something that a person does often, in a regular and repeated way.
A routine is a specific set of habits done in a particular order.
For instance, a regular morning routine could be: wake up, go to the toilet, brush your teeth, get dressed, eat breakfast, drink coffee, go out the door. The whole is a routine, the individual aspects are habits.
If your days are more or less the same every day, with perhaps some deviation over the weekend, then you have a daily routine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I go out and ride</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/how-i-go-out-and-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:35:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/how-i-go-out-and-ride/</guid>
      <description>I was born in the &amp;rsquo;60s and grew up in the &amp;rsquo;70s and &amp;rsquo;80s. In other words, I am definitely pre-internet and pre-mobile phones. When I went out to play or ride my bike no-one had a clue as to where I was, and at times neither did I. Imagine going out without notifications from WhatsApp, email, and social media accounts, without GPS-tracking and online maps&amp;hellip; I explored most of the Netherlands with only a physical map in my back pocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diet or lifestyle change?</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/diet-lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 11:54:14 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/diet-lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s really very simple:
A diet is temporary, a lifestyle change is for ever.
When you are on a diet you temporarily change your eating habits to achieve a certain outcome - most commonly weight loss - before returning to your previous eating habits.
A lifestyle change however, consists of adopting healthy overall habits that promote long-term health and weight control. Further more, diets focus on food intake, while lifestyle changes combine what you eat along with other factors that affect your overall health, such as physical activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivational quotes</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:46:03 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need a bit of motivation. I don&amp;rsquo;t always want to go outside and ride, even knowing that after 20 - 30 minutes I usually can&amp;rsquo;t fathom why I didn&amp;rsquo;t go out earlier. When I need a pick-me-up, I tend to watch a few motivational videos by Jocko Willink and David Goggins telling me to get my shit together and get after it. It works.
Arthur Conan Doyle When the spirits are low, when the day appears dark, when work becomes monotonous, when hope hardly seems worth having, just mount a bicycle and go out for a spin down the road, without thought on anything but the ride you are taking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training zones</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/training-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:17:10 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/training-zones/</guid>
      <description>What are training zones? Training zones are basically exercise intensity levels, and the period within each has a direct effect on how productive your training is. Different types of exercises determine for how long you should ideally train within each zone. Simply put, if you are training for endurance then the lower end training zones are your goal, if sudden, high-speed, explosive break-aways are your thing, then you will need to train more often in the higher end training zones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart rates</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/heart-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:07:23 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/heart-rates/</guid>
      <description>Knowing your heart rate data points is the best way to establish your training zones. However, they are neither easy to define nor to measure.
Definitions Heart rate: your heart rate, or pulse, is the number of times your heart beats per minute at any given moment. Heart rates vary from person to person. It’s lower when you’re at rest and higher when you exercise.
MHR = Maximum Heart Rate: literally the maximum number of beats per minute your heart can reach during an all-out strenuous exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating of Perceived Exertion - RPE</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/rpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:10:02 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/rpe/</guid>
      <description>Ideally you would measure exercise intensity by monitoring your heart rate. However, not everyone has a heart rate monitor readily available. You could measure it by stopping and taking your pulse at regular intervals&amp;hellip;But, there is an alternative that works remarkably well: the Rating of Perceived Exertion, or RPE, also known as the Borg scale.
A Rating of Perceived Exertion is perhaps the most basic way to express the intensity you are experiencing during an exercise, and yet for all its simplicity, it has great value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cardio?</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/cardio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:28:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/cardio/</guid>
      <description>Simply put, a cardiovascular exercise or cardio is an exercise that elevates your heart and breathing rates - effectively pumps your heart rate up to 60% - 70% of its maximum - for at least 20 minutes, improving your heart, lungs, and circulatory system.
Types of Cardio Steady State (SS)
Exercising at a continuous, steady effort.
High Intensity Interval Training (HIIT)
Switching between short periods of intense exercise and brief periods of recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the bicycle?</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 10:13:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/bicycle/</guid>
      <description>I come from a cycling nation, so the bicycle is always high on my mind.
Compared to running, cycling has far less impact on your joints, namely knees and hips, it feels less strenuous yet is a great vehicle for improving your health.
Cycling relaxes my mind, after a while, and certainly out in the countryside, it wanders off into all kinds of new and interesting directions. A good exercise brings peace of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICTIA</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ictia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 10:33:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/posts/ictia/</guid>
      <description>Ictia is an acronym in the spirit of René Descartes.
I Cycle Therefore I Am</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/services/</guid>
      <description>Level 1 coaching plan Athlete profile Absolute beginner Duration 1 month What you get Consultation where we&amp;rsquo;ll evaluate your level of fitness, your goals, and potential scheduling issues Basic training plan (25 - 50 kilometers per week) After 2 weeks evaluation and, if needed, training plan update Price €50 Level 2 coaching plan Athlete profile You are no longer an absolute beginner and want to take basic endurance building to the next level Duration 1 month What you get Consultation where we&amp;rsquo;ll evaluate your level of fitness and your goals Structured workout plan designed to match your fitness level and tailored to your cycling goals (50 - 100 kilometers per week) Training zones based on MHR or RPE Weekly evaluation and, if needed, training plan update Device file data analysis (if available) Price €100 All coaching is private and one-on-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Ictia Cycling is a cycling coaching company that helps people develop themselves to be the best they can be. The main focus is on complete beginners and entry-level cyclists. Athletes receive support through one-on-one coaching, educational blogging and focused structured training plans. The mission is to help unique people achieve their personal goals.
Helping unique people achieve personal goals
My story I have been a cyclist whole my life. In my youth I have competed in both road and cyclocross events, ran marathons, and completed full triathlons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me:</title>
      <link>https://ictia.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ictia.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Loading… </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
